So far you have seen that prediction can be done
これまでに モデルベースまたはデータ駆動型のアプローチを使用して
with model based or data driven approaches and you
予測を実行できることを見てきました
learned that model based approaches incorporate
またモデルベースのアプローチは プロセスモデルを使用した物体の
our knowledge of the objects motion dynamics with process models,
運動力学の知識を含み マルチモーダル推定量を使用した操作についての
handle uncertainty on maneuvers using multimodal estimators,
不確実性を扱うことを学習しました そして モデルベースの
and you have seen that there are many ways to implement model based approaches.
アプローチを実装するには多様な方法があることを見てきました
In learning about data driven approaches you saw that there are
データ駆動型アプローチについての学習では データ駆動型アプローチには
many versions of "data driven" approaches and that these approaches
多くのバージョンがあり これらのアプローチはトレーニングデータから
can extract subtle patterns from training data which means they can
難解なパターンを抽出できるので 特定の運転状態に
produce predictions which are very well tailored to a specific driving situation.
非常によく合った予測を行うことができることを確認しました
In practice, the best way to do prediction is often by taking
実際には 予測を行う最良の方法では 両タイプのアプローチ
a hybrid approach that takes advantage of the strengths of both types of approaches.
の強みを利用したハイブリッドアプローチをとることが多くなっています
Remember earlier when we talked about how model based approaches
前にモデルベースのアプローチでマルチモーダル推定量を使用して
combine process models with a multimodal estimator?
プロセスモデルを組み合わせる方法について話したことを覚えているでしょうか
Well, the multimodal estimator could be replaced with a machine learning approach.
マルチモーダル推定量は 機械学習アプローチに置き換えることができます
To replace that component with a machine learning approach,
そのコンポーネントを機械学習アプローチに置き換えるために
the type of algorithm we need is a classifier.
必要なアルゴリズムのタイプは分類器です
In the next few slides we will talk about
次のいくつかのスライドでは ナイーブベイズ分類器と呼ばれる
how one such classifier known as Naive Bayes classifier works.
分類器がどのように機能するかについて説明します